＜綱手 : 突然 出来た暗渠に➡
The cave-in that suddenly occurred
swallowed up the siblings.
そのきょうだいは
飲み込まれていった。
弥彦と小南と長門。
Yahiko, Konan and Nagato,
who call themselves Team Jiraiya,
チーム・ジライヤを名乗る３人は
すぐに そのあとを追った。
immediately went after them.
しかし
シカマルは動こうとしなかった＞
But, Shikamaru did not budge.
((いの : まずいよ。
(チョウジ)あの子たち 助けなくちゃ。
This is bad.
We have to save those kids!
(シカマル)待てよ。
(２人)えっ？
Wait!
ダメだ 行くな。
We can't. Don't go.
(いの)どうして？
(チョウジ)シカマル…))
Why?
Shikamaru!
"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Order of Priority
(ナルト)ん？ おっと！
The enemy's up ahead!
Watch out!
(サスケ)敵だ 気をつけろ！
What is that?
《ネジ : 何だ？ あれは…》
What do you see, Hinata?
(キバ)どうだ？ ヒナタ。
Looks like the ground caved in.
(ヒナタ)地面の崩落があったみたい。
(シノ)シカマルたちは見つかったか？
Do you see Shikamaru
and his team?
No... There's no a sign of them.
いえ 見当たらない。
I can't track their scent
because of the cave-in.
(キバ)崩落のせいで
ニオイが かき消されちまってる。
ゴホッ もうちょっと
落ち着くのを待たねえと➡
I won't be able to
until the dust settles.
無理だな。
(赤丸)ヘックシュン！
I can't believe the cave-in
could be just a coincidence.
偶然起こった崩落とは思えないな。
Hey, can you hear me?
(弥彦)お～い！ 聞こえるか!?
Hey, kids!
チビども！ お～い！
Hey!
Please answer us!
(小南)お願い返事して。
どこなの？ 助けに行くから。
Where are you?
We're coming to save you!
Could they have been swept away?
この先に流されて…。
Let's go!
行くぞ。
My... My eyes... did this again...
(長門)俺が… 俺の眼が
またあの子たちを。
They did this to those kids...
Nagato.
《長門…》
Look...
とにかく あの子たちを
見つけだすことが先決だ。
we have to find
those kids first.
Just focus on that right now.
今は それだけ考えろ。
Is this really okay?
本当にいいのかな
僕たちも助けに行かなくて。
Are you sure we don't have
to help rescue them?
Those guys are on their way.
やつらが向かった。
That's not the point...
そういう問題じゃなくて。
なんか まずいっていうか。
It just doesn't seem right...
Think about our priorities.
優先順位を考えろ。
Right now, our team captains
have been taken
俺たちは今 班長がさらわれて➡
and our mission is at a standstill.
任務がストップした状態なんだぞ。
一刻も早く他の班と連携して➡
It's our priority to regroup
with the other teams
and come up with a plan of action.
事態の対処を
しなけりゃならねえんだ。
I know that, but...
それはわかってる。 けど…。
The shinobi who were here
in the village have gone to rescue them.
(シカマル)この村にいた忍が
助けに行った。
俺たちには
俺たちのすべきことがある。
We have to do what
we came here to do.
めんどくせえがよ。
Even if it is a drag...
We can't afford to be indecisive.
迷ってちゃいらんねえんだ。
Let's move to a bigger area
キバたちが探知しやすいように
もっと広い場所へ行くぞ。
where Kiba and Akamaru
can track us easily.
The Leaf isn't coming after us.
木ノ葉のやつら 来やしねえな。
これで
やつらの根っこはわかった。
Now we know what
they're really like inside.
もう十分だろう。
This should be good enough.
I'll let him know
just what happened.
このまま ありのままを
あの人に伝えればいい。
ん？ 弥彦 小南！
Yahiko! Konan!
この横穴…。
This tunnel...
Hey!
おい。
What's the matter?
どうした？ 小南。
These walls... this tunnel...
この壁 このトンネル自体…。
Were they... created naturally?
これって自然にできたもの？
W-What?!
な なんだ!?
Lord Mashima... Lord Mashima...
(カヤ)マシマ様 マシマ様…。
Please protect my sons!
どうか息子たちを
お助けくださいませ。
Please... Please...
どうか どうか… あの子たちが
無事でありますよう➡
Please protect them
and keep them safe!
お守りくださいませ。
(シカマル)すみません
祈りの邪魔しちまったみたいで…。
I'm sorry to interrupt your prayers...
We're just passing through, but...
通りすがりの者ですが… これは？
What is this?
マシマ様です。
村の地中におわせられ➡
It's Lord Mashima.
He sleeps beneath the earth...
... and protects our village.
その眠りによって
村をお守りくださっております。
あの その村に
何かあったんですか？
Did something happen
in the village?
私たちは マシマ様を起こさぬよう➡
We maintained a modest,
peaceful way of life,
so as not to awaken Lord Mashima.
静かに 慎ましやかに
暮らしておりました。
(カヤ)それが
ついこの間のことです。
But then, just recently,
何者かが現れ➡
strangers came to our village
and warned us it might
become a battlefield.
村が戦いの場になるかもしれない
と言うのです。
They told us to evacuate to
a safer place for a while.
安全な場所へ
しばらく避難しろと。
We were forced to leave our village.
私たちは無理やり
村を追われてしまいました。
でも 私の息子が２人
村に戻ってしまい➡
But...
My two boys returned
to the village...
連れ戻そうとしたのですが
子供の足には敵わず➡
I tried to go after them,
but they were much faster
and we got separated.
はぐれてしまいました。
That's why I'm praying to
Lord Mashima for their safety.
だから こうしてマシマ様に➡
息子たちの無事を
お願いしていたのです。
マシマ様…。
Lord Mashima?
くるわ。
でかいぞ！
Here it comes!
It's huge!
これって…。
What is it?
Not good!
まずい 逃げ場がねえ！
There's no place to escape!
You saved us, Nagato...
助かったぜ 長門。
ありがとう。
Thank you.
We barely made it.
ギリギリだった。
今の何なんだよ。
What was that just now?
I don't know.
わからない。
とにかく 早くあの子たちを。
We have to get to the kids.
What is that?
(リー)何ですか あれは！
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
Kakashi Sensei...
カカシ先生。
Come here,
if you want to save them.
助けたければ来い。
来なければ処刑を行う。
If you don't, I'll execute them.
Don't move!
Guy Sensei!
動くな！
ガイ先生！
Calm down!
(テンテン)落ち着きなさいよ！
やつらの罠だ。
Don't fall for their trap!
We have to get word of this
俺たちが やるべきことは➡
to the Leaf Village
as soon as possible.
一刻も早く
木ノ葉へ現状を伝えること。
Yes.
We'll have to break up
into two teams.
うむ ここへ残る者と
木ノ葉へ連絡を取る者➡
One stays here, the other goes
to notify the village.
二手に分かれるか。
No... there's a chance
we'll be ambushed on the way.
いや途中
待ち伏せされている可能性もある。
We have to maintain our combat power
as much as possible.
できるだけ
戦力を分散させないほうがいい。
You'll abandon your friends...
to follow the rules.
仲間を見捨てて 掟に従う…。
So the essence of the Hidden Leaf
has been passed down
木ノ葉隠れの里の本質は➡
お前たち 若い下忍にも
徹底されているということか…。
to its younger generation too.
That's right.
And that's how it should be.
そうだ… それでいい。
Whoever he is, that guy
is trying to challenge us...
何者かは知らないが
やつは 俺たちを挑発し➡
and break up our strength.
その力を
分散させようとしてるんだ。
I'm...
俺は… 俺は お前と違う。
なに!?
I'm not like you.
– What?
– I'll never turn my back on them!
放ってなんか おけねえってばよ！
– Naruto!
– Why that—!
(サクラ)ナルト！
この！ 戻ってこい！
Come back!
I'll go!
Take care of things here!
俺が行く！ あとは頼んだ！
Neji!
ネジ！
Big brother...
We lost Kenta!
(コミチ)お兄ちゃん…
ケンタと はぐれちゃった。
We'll find him later.
(アシタバ)あとで ちゃんと探すから。
ほんとだよ！
You promise?
Big brother!
お兄ちゃん！
(２人)うわ～！
Big brother, I'm scared!
お兄ちゃん 怖いよ！
大丈夫。
It's all right.
(２人)うわ～！
Kenta!
ケンタ！
Hey, Shikamaru.
ねぇ シカマル こんなことやめようよ。
Let's not do this.
I don't think this is right.
やっぱ よくないと思うんだ。
Deities are supposed to be
inside these shrines, right?
祠って 神様とかそんなの
祀ってあるんじゃないの？
You're asking for
divine punishment!
バチ当たるって。
I knew it. I was right, after all.
(シカマル)やっぱりな
思ったとおりだぜ。
Okay...
さてと マシマ様と
ご対面といきますか。
Let's go meet this Lord Mashima.
What?
This is—!
(チョウジ)えっ!?
(いの)これって！
Come on!
来いよ
三枚におろしてやるからよ！
I'll filet you into three pieces!
Nagato!
長門！
There they are!
いたっ！
来る！
It's coming!
What? A second one?!
何？ ２体目！
Stay away!
わぁ 来るな！
Expansion Jutsu!
倍化の術！
Human Boulder!
肉弾戦車！
わぁ！
Komichi!
コミチ！
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
影首縛りの術 成功！
You guys...
お前ら。
... came.
来てくれたのか。
What happened to Neji and Naruto?
ネジとナルト君は いったい どこに？
What was that just now?
今のは 何だったの？
It's probably some kind
of time-space jutsu.
おそらく 一種の時空間忍術だ。
But who could use such
a high-level ninjutsu?
でも そんな高等忍術を
いったい誰が？
Damn it...
クソッ！ あいつのせいで
余計な手間が…。
Thanks to him,
we have more trouble to deal with.
うっ うぅ…。
Where are we?
ここは？
さあな。
I don't know...
Are you the one responsible
for all this?
貴様が 今度の事件の仕掛け人か。
Hey!
おい コラ！ カカシ先生とか
木ノ葉の人たちとか返しやがれ！
Return Kakashi Sensei and
everyone else from the Hidden Leaf!
Or else... you're gonna get it!
さもねえと
ひでえ目にあわすぞ！
Naruto, get away from him.
ナルト その男から離れろ。
Don't butt in!
邪魔すんなってばよ！
今こいつと➡
I'm about to settle this right now!
話をつけてる
ところなんだからよ！
Look at his eyes.
そいつの目を見ろ。
えっ？
Huh?
あっ！
The Byakugan?
白眼!?
You're no match for him.
お前の手に負える相手じゃない。
Who are you?
貴様は何者だ？
なぜ白眼を持つ？
How do you possess the Byakugan?
Don't tell me you have ties
to the Hyuga?
まさか 日向に縁ある者なのか？
Look at the cloud of dust...
あの土煙を見るがいい。
Your comrades did that.
お前たちの仲間が
この里で行った所業の結果だ。
What happened?
何があった？
They put their village's rules
before the lives of children.
この里の童たちの命より
自分たちの掟を優先する…。
The Hidden Leaf hasn't changed
a bit in all these years.
相変わらず 木ノ葉隠れの里は➡
昔から何ひとつ
変わっていないんだな。
What would you know
about the Hidden Leaf?
貴様に 木ノ葉の何がわかる。
Oh, I know plenty.
ああ わかるさ。
In fact, I know more
than anyone presently here.
少なくとも
ここにいる誰よりもな。
Follow me...
俺についてくるがいい…
日向ネジ。
Neji Hyuga.
If you want to know
the ugly truth
木ノ葉隠れの里が
ひた隠しにしてきた真実を➡
that the Hidden Leaf has covered up
in this village.
知りたかったらな。
What?
《何なんだ？
何言ってんだよ!? あいつ》
What is he talking about?
yumemiru toraburumeikaa
A dreaming troublemaker
hitori de dekiru furi o shite
Acting like he can do everything alone
furueru hiza o daite tsuyogatteru
Pretending to be strong
as he holds his shaking knees still
wagamama kogitsune fuaitaa
Spoiled fox cub fighter
hatenaga uzumaita sekai
In a world swirling with questions
mienai kizuna musunde hashitteku
He ties invisible bonds and keeps on running
mado kara tobasu kamihikouki sora aokute
A paper airplane hurled out of a window into the blue sky
anata ga naitekureta kara tsuyoku nareta no kana
You cried for me, Maybe that's why I grew strong
saa, yaru dake yattemiyou yo
Come on, let's do what we can
kore ga yume demo ii jan
So what if this is a dream?
senobi toka shichattemo ii janai? (oh)
It's okay to push ourselves to the limit, right? (Oh)
i wanna be with you
I  wanna  be  with  you
(go go) yurase emoushon
(Go go) Let your emotions go
(let's go) kitto daijoubu
(Let's go) It will be all right
(go go) aozora no hate made tobashiteyuke
(Go go) Let it fly to the farthest reaches of the blue sky
Let's hurry back to the village and
report our present status.
今回は
テレビせとうち➡
We don't want
any more casualties.
開局30周年
記念スペシャルです。
What are you saying?
威勢よくまいりましょう
『あばれ太鼓』。
It's not just Guy Sensei,
but Neji is missing!
As well as Naruto,
who's on your team!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Masked Man"
This all happened because
he was being out of line!